[
    {
        "question": "Which one of the following is the size of int arr[9] assuming that int is of 4 bytes?",
        "optionA": "9",
        "optionB": "36",
        "optionC": "35",
        "optionD": "None of the above",
        "answer": "36"
    },

    {
        "question": "Which one of the following is the process of inserting an element in the stack?",
        "optionA": "insert",
        "optionB": "add",
        "optionC": "push",
        "optionD": "pop",
        "answer": "push"
    },

    {
        "question": "When the user tries to delete the element from the empty stack then the condition is said to be a ____",
        "optionA": "Underflow",
        "optionB": "Overflow",
        "optionC": "Garbage collection",
        "optionD": "None of these",
        "answer": "Overflow"
    },

    {
        "question": "Which one of the following is not the application of the stack data structure",
        "optionA": "String reversal",
        "optionB": "Recursion",
        "optionC": "Backtracking",
        "optionD": "Asynchronous data transfer",
        "answer": "Asynchronous data transfer"
    },

    {
        "question": "Which data structure is mainly used for implementing the recursive algorithm?",
        "optionA": "Queue",
        "optionB": "Stack",
        "optionC": "Binary tree",
        "optionD": "Linked list",
        "answer": "Stack"
    },

    {
        "question": "Which of the following is the infix expression?",
        "optionA": "A+B*C",
        "optionB": "+A*BC",
        "optionC": "ABC+*",
        "optionD": "None of the above",
        "answer": "A+B*C"
    },

    {
        "question": "What is another name for the circular queue among the following options?",
        "optionA": "Square buffer",
        "optionB": "Rectangle buffer",
        "optionC": "Ring buffer",
        "optionD": "None of the above",
        "answer": "Ring buffer"
    },

    {
        "question": "Which one of the following is not the type of the Queue?",
        "optionA": "Linear Queue",
        "optionB": "Circular Queue",
        "optionC": "Double ended Queue",
        "optionD": "Single ended Queue",
        "answer": "Single ended Queue"
    },

    {
        "question": "What is the maximum number of children that a node can have in a binary tree?",
        "optionA": "3",
        "optionB": "2",
        "optionC": "1",
        "optionD": "0",
        "answer": "2"
    },

    {
        "question": "Which of the following has search effeciency of ÎŸ(1)",
        "optionA": "Tree",
        "optionB": "Heap",
        "optionC": "Linked List",
        "optionD": "Hash Table",
        "answer": "Hash Table"
    },

    {
        "question": "Which one of the following is the correct option to create a new node?",
        "optionA": "ptr= (node*)malloc(sizeof(node*))",
        "optionB": "ptr=(node)malloc(sizeof(node))",
        "optionC": "ptr=(node*)malloc(sizeof(node))",
        "optionD": "None of the above",
        "answer": "ptr=(node*)malloc(sizeof(node))"
    },

    {
        "question": "Recursion uses more memory space than iteration because",
        "optionA": "every recursive call has to be stored",
        "optionB": "it uses stack instead of queue",
        "optionC": "Both A and B are true",
        "optionD": "None of above are true",
        "answer": "every recursive call has to be stored"
    },

    {
        "question": "Which one of the following techniques is not used in the Binary tree?",
        "optionA": "Randomized traversal",
        "optionB": "Preorder traversal",
        "optionC": "Postorder traversal",
        "optionD": "Inorder traversal",
        "answer": "Randomized traversal"
    },

    {
        "question": "The necessary condition to be checked before deletion from the Queue is__",
        "optionA": "Overflow",
        "optionB": "Underflow",
        "optionC": "Front value",
        "optionD": "Rear value",
        "answer": "Underflow"
    },

    {
        "question": "Which one of the following is not the application of the Queue data structure?",
        "optionA": "Resource shared between various systems",
        "optionB": "Data is transferred asynchronously",
        "optionC": "Load balancing",
        "optionD": "Balancing of symbols",
        "answer": "Balancing of symbols"
    }
]